Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
"Great Detective Conan"
"Challenge to Kudo Shin'ichi"
Oi, this is bad!
This is the sort of atmosphere
where you get an explosion!
Shin'ichi, hurry and remember!
I know!
Tea. Tea...
Oi!
"When was the day you last drank tea?"
Oh, that was close, that was close.
Shin'ichi, did you remember?
It'd be impossible to remember a date like that.
Anyhow, it was just luck,
wasn't it, boy detective?
No, you're wrong.
I didn't input anything.
Eh?
Then, who...
Damn!
That's right...
This date is...
That sad incident that took place at...
...the famous film director's villa.
Ah...
Shin'ichi's Childhood Friend
Mori Ran
I never thought...
...that you and I would get together like this.
I love you.
I want you.
That's it, now kiss! A hot kiss!
Kiss?
That wasn't in the script, now was it?!
Go with the flow, go with the flow.
"Movie Director
Nagata Akihiro"
This detective works by shaking up a
woman's heart while getting closer to the truth.
That's why a kiss is essential.
"Newcomer Actress - Ikusuki Saori"
Let's do it.
High School Student Detective
Kudo Shin'ichi
Hmmf. Why not do it?
Fool. I couldn't do that.
"Shin'ichi and Ran's Fellow Student
Suzuki Sonoko"
What's wrong with a kiss?
Director Nagata went to a lot of trouble
to direct your acting.
Director Nagata is one of the
biggest directors in Japan, you know.
So you shouldn't miss this chance!
I'm not that big a deal.
Hey, what's this "chance"?
You said you wanted us to
keep you company for a play...
...I certainly didn't hear anything about
asking Shin'ichi to take part in any love scenes.
Then...
Do you two want to give it a try?
A passionate love scene.
Here you go.
Thank you very much.
"Villa Manager
Ishihara Kana"
Could it be you two haven't kissed?
Here's how you kiss.
Incredible...
My, that is hot.
"Actress
Nagata Chisato"
Ah! It's the actress Nagata Chisato.
Isn't she his wife?
Chisato...
You lied about shooting a film.
As I thought, you were doing this.
You thieving cat!
When you use a person's husband like this,
you're a woman who's even below a thieving cat!
What are you doing?!
If you can't manage your own husband,
then don't go shouting off your big mouth at me!
I don't know if you're
all that great an actress...
...but you got your roles
using your body, didn't you?!
I won't allow this!
If you can do it, go ahead and do it!
Oi, oi, shape up already...
Let it go, Chisato.
Saori's my lover, so I'll be choosing her
for the lead in my next project.
And you shouldn't let it
irritate you like this, now should you?
It's been my ideal that my wife and lover
would be on good terms and get along together.
The three of us should have fun
and live our lives fully... Right?
Somehow...
this feels like the world of adults.
I know, let's have tea! Right?
I have some superb black tea.
Kana, please prepare it.
Certainly.
If you'd like, you guys can join us.
Ah, no...
Of course we will. We'd love to.
The pride of my collection.
Venetian Meissen teacups...
They're all world masterpieces.
You guys can pick out any cup you'd like.
These are dreamy, aren't they?
Which one will you pick?
I'm not sure.
Far greater than any play, you're the source
of some serious hurt, Director.
You're saying some scary things.
How about it?
Wouldn't you like to
participate in my life, too?
I seriously can't follow this old guy.
Are you still undecided?
Shall I take this one?
No, do I feel like this one today?
What a nice fragrance.
It's a Framboise tea made in Ceylon.
Well then, let's enjoy our teatime.
Just a minute.
Your favorite Ponisshu sugar cubes...
Whenever we have tea at home,
you always put one in, don't you?
A thieving cat wouldn't know that.
Didn't you just poison in it?
Oh my.
The only thing I put in it was love.
Right?
This is an interesting opening, isn't it?
This is how it should have
looked from the beginning.
Well then, let's start over.
Life begins with a hot cup of tea.
Itadakimasu.
Dear!
Director!
Nagata-san! Nagata-san!
He's dead...
This is...
...the odor of almonds.
It's cyanide!
No...
It's a lie.
Ma'am! Ma'am!
Well then, if you would please.
Please go back inside.
Until the jurisdictional police arrive,
don't take even a single step out yet.
All of you are suspects
and also witnesses at the same time.
Suspects?
Even you, the famous high school
student detective, are no exception.
What's going on, Shin'ichi?
Why are we being treated as suspects?
You guys have gotten involved in
this terrible mess, too, haven't you?
Well, me too, though.
Judging from the situation...
...it's apparent someone killed Director Nagata
by putting potassium cyanide into his tea.
Problem is...
...who was it and how did they get
the potassium cyanide into his tea?
We first have to consider Manager Kana-san,
who brought in the tea.
But Kana-san only brought in the one server
and poured tea to everyone from it.
If the tea in the server did have
potassium cyanide in it...
...then all of us here would have died.
Could she have spread the cyanide beforehand
inside just the cup that Director Nagata used?
No, that would've been impossible.
All of us randomly chose the teacups
that we liked from the cupboard.
It would be quite impossible
to predict which cup...
...the Director would choose
and put cyanide inside just that one.
If their forecast was off even a little,
then someone else would have died.
That's true...
Well? How is that woman?
She's resting soundly.
I wonder what her intentions are?
Losing consciousness like that
just as soon as her husband died.
Wasn't it you?
The one who killed the Director.
Why would I do that?
I know that.
Neither you nor I had a motive to.
There's only one person here with a motive.
"Evil Woman"
The one who couldn't forgive
her husband for having an affair...
Chisato-san?
Didn't she put cyanide on that sugar cube?
"Ponisshu sugar cubes..."
But, the one who drank the Director's tea first
was Chisato-san herself, wasn't it?
If she had put the cyanide
in the center of the sugar cube...
...and then drank from the cup before it melted,
she'd be fine, wouldn't she?
But didn't she expressly stir it?
Even if it was a little later,
she would've died herself.
That would be too dangerous, wouldn't it?
Collagen time!
Collagen?
I have to take it at regular times.
An actresses' life is her skin, isn't it?
Is this the sort of time to be taking that?
What is this?
It's potassium cyanide!
- Eh?
Why would potassium cyanide
be in Saori-san's purse...
Are you the criminal?
Don't even joke about that!
That isn't my purse!
This is.
This one's mine.
That's that woman's purse.
Why is this?
I asked the Director for a purse, so he
bought me one the same as that woman's.
He thought it'd be funny
if I showed up with it.
With that...
I guess the criminal is Chisato-san?
Ah, Ma'am.
"Ma'am?"
Where am I?
Who... are you people?
You really don't remember anything?
She's also forgotten her own name...
When a person receives a big enough shock...
...I've heard that they can lose their memories.
The sensation of not wanting to remember
blocks off all memories of the past.
It seems to be a kind of defense instinct.
She's play-acting!
Isn't it a little too convenient to have
committed a murder and then lost her memory?
Murder?
Saori-san!
I'll tear this lying woman's mask off!
Here are your true colors!
"'Femme fatale' Nagata Chisato"
Go on! Take a good, hard look!
You put your own adultery off on a shelf while
saying you can't allow your husband's adultery.
You killed your husband
for your own selfish reasons.
You're a devil woman!
Lies...
Just how far do you intend to
go on feigning ignorance?!
You were always putting on these
performances in order to trick the Director!
The Director was saying you'd even act in bed.
You may be intending to escape from this crime
by saying you don't remember anything...
...but I will never allow that to happen!
Act properly and confess!
You lying bitch!
Stop it...
Have you really lost your memories?
Ran, Kudo-kun, a moment.
I think I know the man she was with here.
You know him?
Yeah. Kimura Keisuke.
He was an actor with a small theater group...
...who committed suicide 2 months after
this magazine was published.
Suicide?!
A famous actress and totally unknown actor.
No matter how you look at it,
they're unbalanced, aren't they?
That's why even if Chisato-san tempted
some hot young man to kill her boredom...
...rumors are she abandoned him in the end.
Was that the reason why he committed suicide?
"'Femme fatale' Nagata Chisato"
Shin'ichi? Why are you taking a photo?
"Evil Woman"
I thought by doing this,
I might remember a little something.
Have you remembered anything?
No, nothing.
I wonder what this room is?
Do you want to see inside?
Yes.
My husband's room?
I wonder what sort of person
my husband was.
What did he do?
He was a movie director.
Movie... director...
This is...
This is the rehearsal hall.
Director Nagata would gather his staff...
...and, before he would shoot, he would
have them rehearse here without fail.
Of course, you as well.
Me, too?
Yes.
Ah... I can't...
I can't remember anything...
"There are no mistakes in her behavior..."
"Is it acting?"
"Or else is it real..."
"Summer... Storm..."
That was the first work you
and Director Nagata made together.
This is... my husband...
In these photos,
I seem to be having a lot of fun.
Sad, isn't it...
Not being able to remember
such fun memories.
Um...
Did I really murder my husband?
If that's so...
Then I'm afraid of myself...
"A AUK KEEN SKI."
What does this mean...
"Glegle Translate"
"Sea sparrow's sharp ski."
Try the other one...
"A AUK KEEN SKI."
What does this mean...
"Sea sparrow seeks ink."
It's an anagram!
The great detective's worried.
Be quiet.
You don't have a clue for either the motive,
the criminal or their method of killing.
I do know two of them.
Eh? You do know?
All that's left is...
...the method of killing.
I see...
That's how it was!
Eh?
I've seen it.
The one and only truth.
Were you intending to erase the evidence?
The one who killed Director Nagata
with potassium cyanide... was you, wasn't it?
Ishihara Kana-san.
What is this foolishness...
What reason would I have to kill Director Nagata?
The one you were holding a grudge
against wasn't Director Nagata...
...but his wife, Chisato-san.
Kana-san.
Wasn't the man who appeared in this
weekly magazine along with Chisato-san...
...actually your lover?
Kimura Keisuke.
You have on the same good-luck bracelet
that Keisuke-san has in this magazine.
With only that, how could you call us lovers...
On the faceplate of both bracelets
are inscribed some characters of the alphabet.
On Keisuke-san's it's, "A AUK KEEN SKI."
On yours it's, "A AUK SEEK INK."
These are anagrams...
...where if you change the arrangement of
the characters, you create a different meaning.
When you analyze the
11 characters in these anagrams...
...you get "Keisuke Kana."
In other words, both of your names.
Both of your names.
You figured you wanted to
take revenge on Chisato-san...
...who had driven your lover
Keisuke-san into suicide.
Your intended revenge
wasn't to kill Chisato-san...
...but to place the stigma
of being called a murderer on her.
So you tried to kill Director Nagata...
...and then pin the blame
for it on Chisato-san.
How?
Are you saying I placed
the potassium cyanide in the tea?
The potassium cyanide wasn't put in the tea.
It was applied to all of the cups beforehand.
What's more...
...it was applied along this portion of the cups.
But, by applying cyanide
to the right hand side only...
...along this section on the opposite side,
mouths wouldn't touch it.
That way, even if Chisato-san
did taste the Director's tea...
...she wouldn't die.
You normally hold a cup with
your dominant hand, don't you?
Director Nagata was
the only member of our party...
...who was left-handed.
You casually checked us out about that.
From the start you knew
which was Chisato-san's dominant hand.
So whichever cup he would
eventually take from the cupboard...
...the result was that only Director Nagata
would end up taking the potassium cyanide.
The one who switched those purses
was also you, wasn't it?
So that Saori-san would make the mistake of
finding the cyanide in Chisato-san's purse.
Your finishing touch was to have been
wiping the cyanide off all the cups.
I got so far.
Yes, it's just as you say.
This woman...
...was the instigator who toyed with
Keisuke's dream and who drove him to his death!
Keisuke...
...was so thrilled when he
contacted me to say...
...that you had promised him
a co-starring role.
Yet even so, you broke that promise...
...and then abandoned Keisuke like
he was some worn-out dust cloth!
That's why Keisuke...
...despaired about everything and chose death.
He had no choice but to choose that!
I swore revenge.
That worthless woman must die.
Nevertheless, you went and had amnesia.
When a person has lost their memories...
...pining a crime on them has no meaning.
You'd never suffer for all the sins
you had committed in the past.
What on earth was this for...
No.
I think you achieved your goal perfectly.
Your purpose was to a least..
...make her conscious of her past crimes.
Chisato-san...
...your amnesia is a fake, isn't it?
When you entered the pitch-black darkness
of that basement warehouse...
...you didn't hesitate in turning on the lights.
Why, if you had amnesia...
...would you know the location of
that room's light switch?
I didn't think you had noticed.
But why...
...did you put on this amnesia act?
When I woke up, here in this room...
...all of you were making a fuss over
finding the cyanide.
"With that...
I guess the criminal is Chisato-san?"
I had a hunch.
That someone was trying to
pin the guilt for the murder on me.
So I thought by feigning amnesia
I might find out who the murderer was.
But...
...since you saw through me,
I guess my acting still has a ways to go yet.
Kana-san, shall I tell you?
The reason why
I broke my promise with Keisuke.
He had no talent as an actor.
It's just that simple.
For you to have murdered for that man's sake...
...just makes you a foolish woman.
Still, I'm grateful to you.
I was thinking it would be best if
my husband was dead.
Because he had already become
an unnecessary person in my life.
Thank you.
I should have killed you...
You're the one I should have killed!
You're the lowest of women.
I think so, too.
Me, too!
I don't mind.
I can be an actress like that.
Still...
How could the criminal behind this know
that was the last day I had tea?!
They must have been observing you
for a long time now.
Is it true the criminal's been watching us?
Probably.
"Actress"
I already have a bad
premonition about this one...
Doesn't seem to be over yet...
Let's get going! Go on!
Ow!
What is it?!
Somehow... my body's gone numb...
- Ran!
Oi, are you okay?!
"If not given an antidote in time..."
"...she will die."
Damn!
What day is this?!
What should we input?!
Oi, boy detective!
Hurry and remember!
Wait, Ran...
That's it!
This is...
That incident at the cabaret club...
"The Murder Play Surrounding
the No.1 Cabaret Girls"